JUSTIN SCOPELLETI

SOFTWARE/WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

514-754-1427

justin.scopelleti@gmail.com

https://portfolio-kesmek.vercel.app/

https://github.com/Kesmek

EDUCATION

McGill University

Bachelor of Science

Computer Science Major Physics Minor 2017 - 2022



John Abbott College

Diplôme d'études collégiales (DEC) Sciences Program 2015 - 2017



PROJECTS

Discord Bots

Built and maintained several discord bots using typescript, dependency injection and Docker. Hosted on google cloud platform as well as self hosted on a Raspberry PI.

Puncher

An app used for locally tracking your hours for shift work. Built using React Native and TypeScript for cross compatibility with iOS and Android. Includes ability to track hours from multiple different employers at once, managed with Redux.

Daydream

A social media app; a mix of the live interactivity of Twitch and the social aspect of Instagram. Built using React Native, JavaScript + TypeScript for the frontend. The backend used AWS (S3, Lambda, API Gateway, AWS SNS) with JavaScript. Made in collaboration with one other developer which required regular meetings and communication. All code versions were managed with Git + Github.

SUMMARY

I'm a motivated software developer with an interest in building and maintaining performant mobile and web applications. I have worked across the full technology stack for mobile development (React Native, AWS, Node.js) and am currently learning web development. I'm specifically learning to use modern frameworks (Qwik, React) alongside html and css to build interactive websites. I've also experimented with various other technologies including Firebase, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), and Docker to name a few. I am always researching ways of improving my programming skills, find new interesting projects and strive to make each project something I can be proud of.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Banquet Server

Elm Ridge Country Club 2018 - 2023

 Serve and clear tables, following a dynamic schedule provided by the banquet manager. Delegate tasks to my partners and coordinate with the other groups to deliver timely service.

Busboy

Elm Ridge Country Club 2015 - 2022

 Clear and reset tables, help out waiters with small tasks or serving, clean and prepare our stations for the following day, communicate and cooperate with and delegate work to other bussers.

SKILLS

- Tools: Git, Github, Redux, MongoDB, AWS (S3, Lambda, API Gateway), Firebase
- App Development: Used NodeJS +
 TypeScript to create and maintain
 several Discord bot applications. Bots
 interact with the Discord API through a
 library using dependency injection.
 Some deployed in a docker container
 hosted on GCP, others self hosted on
 RaspberryPi using pm2.
- Mobile Development: Used React
 Native and TypeScript alongside many
 of the aforementioned tools to build
 multiple applications for Android and
 iOS.

- Documentation: Wrote structured, example driven, and easily readable documentation on all projects I've worked on. Including the very new Qwik framework.
- Web Development: Used React and TypeScript to create multiple small web pages. Other technologies used: HTML, CSS. Actively working on using and contributing to Qwik, a revolutionary new web framework.
- Languages: Ability to communicate in english fluently, both orally and written.
 Ability to communicate in french at an intermediate level both written and orally.